(indistinct chatter)
(door closes)
- [Man] Yo.
(indistinct comment)
(footsteps)
(door opens)
- [Braxton] Have a seat
right there, in that chair.
(woman crying)
(objects fumbling)
Okay.
(woman crying)
I'm gonna get you some tissues, okay?
- [K. Jones] I need my
inhaler, I can't breathe.
(crying)
- [Braxton] Where's your inhaler?
(woman crying)
(woman breathing heavily)
Can you do me a favor?
Calm down for a second.
'Cause I gotta ask you
something that's gonna...
That I need help with, okay.
(woman breathing heavily)
You have an inhaler you
said, where's it at?
- [K. Jones] In the house.
- [Braxton] Okay.
(woman breathing heavily)
How often do you see them?
- [K. Jones] I'm sorry.
- [Braxton] Okay.
Let me explain to you what's going on.
Your friend, what's her name, Tamiyah?
- [K. Jones] Tamiyah.
- [Braxton] Tamiyah,
you have her phone number?
- [K. Jones] Yeah.
- [Braxton] Can you
show it to me please?
- [K. Jones] It's in my phone-
- [Braxton] Is this your phone?
Can you just gimme that
real quick, please?
(woman breathing heavily)
(woman deep breathing)
Okay.
Tamiyah.
2, 0, 2,
8, 3, 4,
0, 2, 1, 4.
Okay.
What's your last name, sweetie?
- [K. Jones] Jones.
- [Braxton] Jones?
- [K. Jones] Mhm.
- [Braxton] What's your first name?
- [K. Jones] Kenisha.
- [Braxton] Kenisha? Want to spell it for me?
- [K. Jones] K-E-N-I-S-H-A.
- [Braxton] H-A? And what's your address, sweetie?
- [K. Jones] 52-
- [Braxton] 52.
- [K. Jones] 53rd Street Southeast.
- [Braxton] Just 52 53rd Street?
(K. Jones nods)
- [K. Jones] Excuse me.
- [Braxton] That's okay.
- [Braxton] What section of the city is that in?
- [K. Jones] Southeast.
- [Braxton] Is that a house or apartment?
- [K. Jones] House.
- [Braxton] So 52 53rd Street.
- [Braxton] And what's your date of birth?
- [K. Jones] January 5, 2000.
- [Braxton] Okay.
- [Braxton] And what's your phone number?
- [K. Jones] 202-
- [Braxton] Uh-huh.
- [K. Jones] 823-
- [Braxton] 823.
- [K. Jones] 6971.
- [Braxton] When's the last time you talked to Tamiyah?
- [K. Jones] I talked to her on Thursday.
- [Braxton] Uh-huh.
Did somebody call you
while we were in here?
While you were talking to the officers?
Your phone's about to die.
- [K. Jones] Then he called
me and said she died.
- [Braxton] Who?
- [K. Jones] My friend that got shot.
- [Braxton] Okay.
Who called you and told you that?
- [K. Jones] Her brother.
They at the hospital.
[Braxton] Okay.
I'm sorry about what happened
with your friend, okay,
but lemme explain to you what's going on.
Okay, I'm Detective Braxton,
I need to sit down and
ask you some questions
about what happened, okay?
So this is some bad things,
so we can get to the bottom
of what happened, okay?
Ms. Jones? Do you have a nickname, sweetie?
- [K. Jones] Kenn.
- [Braxton] Candy?
[K. Jones] K-E-N.
Let me put my phone on vibrate real quick,
one second.
I'm gonna plug this in,
'cause I'm gonna have to ask
you some questions about it.
So I'm gonna get,
what's this, an Apple?
I'm gonna plug it in and charge it
so I can ask you some
questions about this, okay?
Give me two seconds, I'll be right back.
(door opens and closes)
(object tapping)
(woman crying)
(man speaking in background)
(door opens)
(metal object rattling)
(woman crying)
- [Braxton] Okay.
- [Braxton] Okay, Ms. Jones.
I'm sorry about what happened
with your girlfriend,
but I need to ask you some questions
about what happened.
Can you explain some of that
to me so I can figure out?
Could you do that for me?
- [K. Jones] We was going to get our stuff.
- [Braxton] You say we, who's we?
- [K. Jones] Me, my...
Well, it was supposed to be just me
and Kenzo.
- [Braxton] I'm gonna
ask you a question,
could you speak up a little bit?
'Cause I'm like 53 three years old,
I know you young.
Let me get you some tissues.
(door opens)
(door closes)
(talking in background)
Thanks.
(door opens)
(door closes)
(objects fumbling)
Okay, so you said
it was you?
- [K. Jones] Me, Deshawna, and Kenzo.
Well, it was me and Kenzo but-
- [Braxton] Who's Kenzo?
- [K. Jones] The one that just died.
- [Braxton] Okay.
Y'all call her Kendall?
Okay, y'all call her Kenzo, okay.
- [K. Jones] We were originally going to Tamiyah house
to go get my stuff
and some of Kendall's belongings.
(phone vibrates)
So,
we seen my cousin walkin,
so she was like, "You wanna come with us?"
And she was like, "Yeah."
So we had went,
we was going to Ken,
to Tamiyah's house.
So when we tried, we knocked on the door,
she opened the door, she peeked out like,
then she was like, "What?"
And we was like, "We just
coming to get the stuff,
we not on nothing like."
'Cause she-
- [Braxton] Hold on,
Hey Lou, I'm in an interview, what's up?
- [Lou] I gotcha, just text me.
Have we got that number yet?
- [Braxton] Yeah, I sent it to the Cap,
to everybody in the squad.
I'll send it to you right now.
- [Lou] Okay.
- [Braxton] Bye bye.
- [Lou] Bye.
- [Braxton] Go ahead.
- [K. Jones] But, so we got
in the house or whatever,
then the boyfriend was just holding...
Holding his pocket like this,
and he was like,
he callin his friends,
and I'm like, "For what? We're females."
And him and her, him and
Kendall started arguing.
And like-
- [Braxton] Did the boyfriend
and Kendall start arguing?
- [K. Jones] Yeah.
- [Braxton] Okay, and what was said?
- [K. Jones] He was like,
I don't even know,
'cause I've been going through a lot,
I have like a lot of disorders and stuff.
I black out and stuff.
- [Braxton] Mm hmm.
- [K. Jones] So like, I don't remember
what happened right there.
I just know I heard,
and then she's like,
"I think he shot me."
And we both tried to run,
and then I blacked out and she
was pushin us out the door-
- [Braxton] Who's the she?
- [K. Jones] Tamiyah.
- [Braxton] Was pushing
you out of which room?
- [K. Jones] The door, the house door,
the front door.
And when I got down the...
I don't even know how
I got down the steps,
but I seen Deshawna,
and I was like,
'cause I seen red stuff on the floor,
so I'm thinking Kenzo
had went down the steps.
I'm like, "Where Kenzo?"
She like, "I thought she was with you."
And I'm like, "No."
So we tried to get back in the house,
but the door was locked,
and we was leaving out
and the police was
coming and they was like,
"We tried to get in, the door's locked."
So they had to kick the door in
'cause they locked the door,
and then, that's it.
- [Braxton] Okay.
So let's back up.
So you and Kenzo were going over there.
- [K. Jones] To get the stuff.
- [Braxton] To get the stuff.
How had y'all communicated
with her to let her know-
- [K. Jones] I got some of
my stuff on Thursday,
this Thursday that just passed,
and she was cool about it.
But when I got at the boyfriend,
when I came there that day I had a tote,
and I was getting it from her house,
she was cool about it and stuff.
We was talking about
taking the kids to Launch,
and the trampoline place and stuff.
- [Braxton] So you got kids, too?
- [K. Jones] Yeah, I have a daughter.
- [Braxton] Okay.
- [K. Jones] So, we was on some cool stuff.
It wasn't no like animosity or nothing.
- [Braxton] Right.
- [K. Jones] And he brushed past me
and he went down the steps real fast
and got into a black car,
but I don't know him, so,
he always had animosity from Thursday
to the day when we just seen him,
he had animosity, but I don't know.
- [Braxton] Well, do
you know what his name is?
- [K. Jones] No, I never met him.
That's what I'm sayin.
- [Braxton] When's the
first time you saw him?
'Cause you saw him on Thursday-
- [K. Jones] Thursday, that was
the first time I saw him
on Thursday.
And then today is the
second time I saw him.
- [Braxton] Same dude you saw Thursday
is the same dude you saw today.
Okay.
So when you went over on Thursday,
he was there Thursday?
- [K. Jones] Yeah, and he was leaving,
he was leaving, though.
He brushed past the two
and went down the steps.
As I grabbed the two,
I was going down the steps
and he got in a black car.
But he wasn't driving.
- [Braxton] He wasn't driving?
- [K. Jones] No, he got in the passenger.
- [Braxton] Okay.
So,
on Thursday everything was fine?
- [K. Jones] Yeah, it was cool.
- [Braxton] Did she know
y'all were coming over today?
- [K. Jones] Yes.
- [Braxton] Okay.
Had y'all,
how'd y'all communicate?
- [K. Jones] I told her, I was like...
'Cause she had blocked us
on Instagram and stuff,
and I called her bluff, and I was like,
"I'm about to get the rest of my stuff."
Around on this side stuff-
- [Braxton] Okay.
- [K. Jones] And she was like, "Okay."
That's about when we was telling her,
"We not on nothin."
And she was like all right,
but she was cool about it.
Well, we wasn't really arguing with her,
it was more so arguing with him
'cause he kept doing like this,
and I'm like,
- [Braxton] And that was today?
- [K. Jones] "We're females." Yes.
I'm like, "We're females.
What are you doin?"
And he was like, he calling his friends,
and I'm just like, "We're females."
That's why him and
Kendall started arguing,
and stuff.
And me and her, I don't even remember
what was said.
- [Braxton] Well, did
you text her at all?
- [K. Jones] No.
- [Braxton] Did you send
her anything on Instagram?
- [K. Jones] No, she had
blocked us on Instagram.
- [Braxton] You know
what her Instagram is?
- [K. Jones] Yeah.
- [Braxton] What's
your Instagram, sweetie?
- [K. Jones] K-E-N-
- [Braxton] K-E-N.
- [K. Jones] N-dot-underscore.
- [Braxton] Dot-underscore.
- [K. Jones] Underscore.
- [Braxton] That's it?
- [K. Jones] Mhm. That's my Instagram.
- [Braxton] And what about hers?
- [K. Jones] It's M-Y-Z-
- [Braxton] M-Y-
- [K. Jones] Z-I-E.
- [Braxton] Mhm.
- [K. Jones] E.
- [K. Jones] N-Y-Z.
- [Braxton] N-Y-Z.
- [K. Jones] Z-I-E.
- [Braxton] Another Z?
- [K. Jones] No. I-E-E.
- [Braxton] Mhm.
- [K. Jones] That's it.
- [Braxton] That's it.
- [K. Jones] That's my phone, it's movin.
- [Braxton] Okay.
And that's Tamiyah's.
Have y'all been communicating at all
about anything else?
- [K. Jones] Yeah, we talked
about her daughter and stuff.
- [Braxton] Is that in text or IG?
- [K. Jones] No, like on the phone.
- [Braxton] Okay.
- [K. Jones] And what she was saying
about the Launch and stuff,
and she was like,
"Yeah, I've been trying to get in contact
with her father and stuff."
- [Braxton] Whose father?
- [K. Jones] The baby's.
- [Braxton] Okay.
- [K. Jones] And she was
like, "She gone right now."
And stuff, that's what I'm sayin,
it was no animosity, it was no beef
for this to occur.
- [Braxton] Well, answer this,
when y'all got over there today,
was anybody talking about
money, about something?
- [K. Jones] Yeah, 'cause,
okay so when we left our
stuff in the house, right,
she said she was movin
so she was gonna let us know
when to come get our stuff.
But it was like liquor
and stuff, and I was like,
"You know, if you don't have
the liquor and the stuff,
just give me the money for it."
She was like, "I don't have no money."
- [Braxton] Right.
- [K. Jones] Yeah.
- [Braxton] Okay.
So how did y'all get in the house?
- [K. Jones] She moved back.
At first she was like this,
and we put our foot right there,
but she had moved back and let us in
when I told her we wasn't
trying to do nothing to her.
- [Braxton] Right.
- [K. Jones] 'Cause I was like, "You know me,
we just comin to get this stuff."
And then we just got into
it with the boyfriend.
- [Braxton] So, when you say
we got into it with your boyfriend,
was your cousin upstairs with y'all?
Was it just you?
- [K. Jones] I think she was, yeah.
- [Braxton] Okay.
So, whose foot was in the door?
Was it yours or your girl's?
- [K. Jones] It was mine's.
All I remember is my foot,
and I think my cousin's.
- [Braxton] Okay.
- [K. Jones] I'm not sure.
- [Braxton] So, when y'all go inside.
- [K. Jones] We were standin
in the living room-
- [Braxton] In the living room.
Where else do y'all go at in the house
other than the living room?
- [K. Jones] When I was
still talking to Tamiyah
in the living room,
the boyfriend and Kenzo walked,
I don't know who walked back there first,
but they were both back there.
- [Braxton] You say back there?
- [K. Jones] Yeah, in her room,
'cause her house set up is,
when you open the front
door it's the living room.
[Braxton] Uh-huh.
- [K. Jones] And then this side is the kitchen
and is a room right there in the bathroom
straight across.
And you could go straight
to the room, and-
- [Braxton] So straight to the bedroom.
- [K. Jones] Mm hmm.
Through the kitchen.
- [Braxton] Through the kitchen.
So, were they in the kitchen?
- [K. Jones] Kenzo was in
the door of the kitchen,
and because the kitchen
leads into her bedroom-
- [Braxton] I got you.
- [K. Jones] And I didn't see him right there,
but he was inside the room.
- [Braxton] Okay,
and you could see that?
- [K. Jones] Yeah.
- [Braxton] Okay.
So,
when he's back there with Kenzo.
- [K. Jones] I just said, she
kept saying, "We're females."
They were arguing about,
'cause I guess he kept
reaching for his gun,
she was saying,
"We're females, we not here to do nothing,
we just coming to get the stuff."
'Cause we know,
well, Thursday,
if it was an issue or
something, how he rubbed me off,
we would've brought males with us,
that's what I'm sayin,
we just came to get the stuff real quick
while we on this side.
And that's what I'm sayin,
if I knew who he was,
I would know where the
secret motive is coming from.
But I don't know him at all-
- [Braxton] Right.
- [K. Jones] I don't have no idea who he is.
- [Braxton] Okay.
But this is just the
second time you saw him?
- [K. Jones] Yeah.
- [Braxton] Would you
recognize if you saw him?
- [K. Jones] I think I would, yeah.
- [Braxton] Okay.
Have you ever seen any
pictures with her with him?
- [K. Jones] Yeah, a video.
- [Braxton] You do?
- [K. Jones] Yeah, one of my
other friends sent it to me.
they was like, "Ooh, is
this her new boyfriend?"
I was like, "Girl, I guess."
- [Braxton] Do you have that video?
- [K. Jones] Yeah, I can check.
(phone vibrates)
There it is.
That video right there, you can click it.
This one.
- [Braxton] Y'all with these fancy new smartphones.
Right here?
This the video you talking about?
- [K. Jones] Yeah.
- [Braxton] And that, who's that?
- [K. Jones] That's the girl Tamiyah.
(indistinct audio)
- [Braxton] Can you send me that?
So is this...
You sayin, the boy?
- [K. Jones] Yeah, this him in the back.
- [Braxton] That's him in the back?
- [K. Jones] Mm hmm.
- [Braxton] Can you send me that?
- [K. Jones] What was your number?
- [Braxton] 2-0-2-4-8-6
3-4-1-8.
- [K. Jones] Hold on,
wait a second.
You said.
- [Braxton] 2-0-2
4-8-6
3-4-1-8.
(Kenn comments indistinct)
Did you send it to me that time?
- [K. Jones] Mm hmm.
- [Braxton] Oh, okay.
So that's the boy that you saw today?
- [K. Jones] Yeah.
- [Braxton] And that's the same boy
you saying you saw on Thursday,
and that's the boy that you...
You saw reaching, like he
had something you said?
- [K. Jones] Yeah, it's in the video.
- [Braxton] Okay, in which video?
- [K. Jones] That the detectives got.
- [Braxton] Okay.
How do you know that?
- [K. Jones] 'Cause like
my dad always told me,
"Whenever it's a male,
you always record."
- [Braxton] Oh, so you recorded today?
- [K. Jones] Mm hmm.
- [Braxton] Your dad
sound like a smart man.
- [K. Jones] Yes.
He is.
The detectives was
on pause in there, and stuff.
So it's gonna be like.
- [Braxton] So, when this is going on,
are you inside?
- [K. Jones] Yeah, we were in
the house talkin to her.
- [Braxton] Okay.
- [K. Jones] And he was arguing.
Well, she was saying...
They were arguin, him and Kendall.
And that's when I say he walked,
they walked to the back,
I don't know who walked back there first,
'cause I was looking at her.
- [Braxton] Okay.
Can you send me that?
- [K. Jones] It's 3-4-1-8?
- [Braxton] Yeah, 3-4-1-8,
4-8-6-3-4-1-8.
(chair moving)
So,
where were you at?
So when all that happens, you're saying...
You said when y'all in
the apartment, right,
and they're getting into it,
and she talking about,
"Why you gotta do that, we're girls, we're girls."
And he's reachin,
you were in the living room at that point?
- [K. Jones] Mm hmm.
- [Braxton] Okay.
Your girlfriend, Kendall,
she's still inside the apartment?
- [K. Jones] Yeah, we were
still in the apartment.
- [Braxton] So how do
you all end up outside
and she stays inside?
- [K. Jones] Because remember I told you,
when I heard the shot and stuff,
I don't know how I got down the stairs,
I be blacking out,
but I was down the steps
and I seen red stuff,
so in my head I'm thinking
Kendall left out the apartment.
- [Braxton] So you thought
she left out when you left out?
- [K. Jones] Yeah.
- [Braxton] So you said when
you got out the apartment,
you tried to get back in.
- [K. Jones] Yeah.
'Cause when I asked Deshawna, I was like,
I said, "Where Kendall?"
She said, "She not with you?"
I was like, "No."
So we were coming back up the steps
and we were trying to open the door,
but it was locked,
and we started to hear the sirens
so we went back downstairs.
- [Braxton] Okay.
Did you yell for anybody
or anything like that?
- [K. Jones] No, we called the police.
- [Braxton] Y'all called the police?
- [K. Jones] Mm hmm.
- [Braxton] Okay.
So, did your girlfriend Tamiyah,
what's her name?
- [K. Jones] Tamiyah.
- [Braxton] Did she come out?
- [K. Jones] What they did was,
they locked the front door,
then they left out the back door
and locked that door, too.
- [Braxton] How do you
know they left out the back?
- [K. Jones] Because they
were not in the apartment.
- [Braxton] They
weren't in the apartment?
- [K. Jones] No.
- [Braxton] Okay.
- [K. Jones] And they didn't
come out the front door
because we were still at
the front tryin to get in.
- [Braxton] So the boy that
you showed me in that picture,
that's the same boy you saw on Thursday?
- [K. Jones] Yes.
- [Braxton] That's the
same boy that you videotaped
when the stuff started today?
- [K. Jones] Yes.
- [Braxton] And that's the same boy
that when you say he was walking,
reaching, and your girlfriend
Kendall was talking to him?
That's the same boy?
- [K. Jones] Yes.
- [Braxton] Okay, you just
don't know what his name is?
- [K. Jones] No.
- [Braxton] Okay.
And you said that's supposed
to be her boyfriend?
- [K. Jones] Her boyfriend, yeah.
- [Braxton] And she never
posted what his name is,
or anything like that?
- [K. Jones] No, when I asked her, I was like,
"Who is that?"
She was like, "He not from nowhere."
And I was like, "Yeah, what's his name?"
She wasn't tellin me,
she was bein discreet.
- [Braxton] Being real discreet?
So, your friend that sent you
the page thing about him,
does she know anything about this dude?
- [K. Jones] No, nobody know
of him, that we be with.
- [Braxton] How long
have you known Kendall?
- [K. Jones] I met her in December,
we really started hanging in January.
- [Braxton] How long
have you known Tamiyah?
- [K. Jones] I knew Jim...
I knew Tamiyah since December, as well.
- [Braxton] Since December?
So, are you close?
Did you meet them together, or separate?
- [K. Jones] I've been knew Kendall,
we just never really hung out,
but we all started to
hang together in January.
- [Braxton] Okay.
And you just don't know what happened
to cause this to happen like that?
Nobody,
you didn't have a weapon?
- [K. Jones] No, I got mace on my key chain,
but I didn't attempt to use it.
So, I don't know.
- [Braxton] So when
you heard the gunshot,
where were you at?
- [K. Jones] I was standing beside her.
Not beside her,
but adjacent, from her at an angle.
- [Braxton] Right, and you said
you heard her say something about-
- [K. Jones] She said, "I think I got shot."
'Cause I didn't know
which one of us got shot.
- [Braxton] Right.
- [K. Jones] I just heard it,
I didn't even know anybody got shot,
she was like this,
we were both trying to run.
She was like, "I think I got shot."
- [Braxton] And she said
that to you, "I think"-
- [K. Jones] Yeah, and we were running
then, I don't know,
my vision went out.
- [Braxton] Okay.
So,
where do you think your
girlfriend would go
if something like this happened?
- [K. Jones] I would say to her mom house,
but I don't think she would go there.
- [Braxton] Does she have-
- [K. Jones] 'Cause she got four kids,
so it is not like she can't go,
you feel what I'm sayin?
- [Braxton] Right.
- [K. Jones] She don't have
nowhere else to go.
- [Braxton] Well, how
many kids were there today
when you got there?
- [K. Jones] One.
- [Braxton] Just one.
Do you know where her other kids were at?
- [K. Jones] No.
- [Braxton] Okay.
So, she have a car?
- [K. Jones] No.
- [Braxton] You don't
know if he has a car
'cause you saw him getting a car-
- [K. Jones] In the passenger-
- [Braxton] Passenger's seat.
- [K. Jones] Yeah.
- [Braxton] And he was
wearing the same stuff
you saw in the video that you showed me?
- [K. Jones] Yeah, today,
that was the video today.
- [Braxton] Okay.
Did you see the gun?
- [K. Jones] I seen,
no, when he shot I didn't see the gun,
but he had something right here,
but I can't remember,
my memory is, got holes
in it or something.
- [Braxton] I can understand.
Did he say anything to y'all?
Did you remember before he-
- When he was shooting he
said, "I just came home."
- [Braxton] That's what
he said, "I just came home"?
- [K. Jones] Yeah.
Yeah he did.
- [Braxton] And that's all he said,
"I just came home."
And what did you take that to mean?
- [K. Jones] At the moment,
I didn't think nothing of it
until when I was talking to
the detective and she was like,
"Think back."
And I remember Tamiyah bein on the phone
with people in jail,
but I don't remember their names.
- [Braxton] Okay.
So when you heard the
term, "I just came home."
What did you take that to mean?
- [K. Jones] Like, he wouldn't
do anything like that,
you just came home.
- [Braxton] Just came home from-
- [K. Jones] Yeah, from jail.
- [Braxton] From jail, okay.
So your cousin,
was she inside when it happened?
- [K. Jones] I don't remember.
- [Braxton] You don't remember?
- [K. Jones] No.
- [Braxton] Okay.
And your cousin's the other young lady
that's sitting out there, okay.
Do you have any kind of communication,
do you mind showing me the last...
Your text message, so
I can see the last time
y'all communicated with each other.
- [K. Jones] Who?
- [Braxton] You and Tamiyah?
- I deleted everything
when she blocked me.
- [Braxton] Oh you did-
- [K. Jones] So I had to
call from block, here.
- [Braxton] Okay.
So you don't have nothing else
on your phone from her?
- [K. Jones] No.
- [Braxton] Okay.
- [K. Jones] I mean,
I think Kenzo texted her today.
- [Braxton] Kenzo did?
- [K. Jones] Yeah, but I don't know her phone,
one of the detectives got it.
- [Braxton] One of her
phones, the detective has?
And you know, Kenzo texted
her today, you said.
- [K. Jones] Yeah, and she called her as well.
- [Braxton] Right, and she called her.
So she didn't block Kenzo,
she just blocked you?
- [K. Jones] No.
(phone vibrating)
- [Braxton] Okay.
- [K. Jones] I don't know who that is.
- [Braxton] And the
detective has her phone.
- [K. Jones] Mm hmm.
- [Braxton] And how do you know
the detective has her phone?
- [K. Jones] Because her cousin
was trying to get the phone
and he was like, "No, we gotta keep this."
And he gave it to her.
- [Braxton] Okay.
And you knew that there was some kind
of text messages in there between her and-
- [K. Jones] Kenzo.
- [Braxton] Kenzo.
Between Tamiyah and Kenzo.
So she told her y'all were coming over
to get your stuff?
- [K. Jones] Yeah, she said okay.
Maybe,
like in my head,
I'm thinking maybe the guy
wasn't there at the time,
he just got there when
we probably got there.
I don't know.
'Cause I don't know him
so I don't know his motive of anger or...
I don't know.
This shit just raise my blood pressure.
- [Braxton] Does Kendall have any kids?
- [K. Jones] No.
- [Braxton] Okay.
How long did y'all live with Tamiyah?
- [K. Jones] We didn't
necessarily live with her.
- [Braxton] Stay over,
how long did y'all stay over at?
- [K. Jones] We had been there for months,
we'd go home, come back,
and stuff like that.
- [Braxton] Hmm.
And other than the dude saying,
"I just came home."
There was nothing else that
you can remember being said,
other than your girl saying,
"Hey, we females, we females."
- [K. Jones] No.
- [Braxton] So after you heard the shot,
you came out in the hall,
you got out the apartment?
- [K. Jones] No, we both did like this,
to make sure our face and stuff.
- Right, and she said-
- [K. Jones] She said, "I think I got shot."
And we both were running,
but I blacked out, so I don't remember.
- [Braxton] Okay.
How many gunshots did you hear?
- [K. Jones] I really don't remember.
- [Braxton] Okay.
But she said, "I think I got hit."
And then when you got out in the hallway,
you realized when you talked
to your cousin, it's like,
"Where's she at? She's not with us."
- [K. Jones] Yeah, because
I thought I seen blood.
I just seen something red though
so I thought it was blood.
So I'm thinking she
down there and I'm like,
"Where Kenzo at?"
She was like, I" thought
she was with you."
And I'm like, "No."
So we went back to the apartment
trying to open the door,
but it was locked.
- [Braxton] You said it was locked.
- [K. Jones] Mm hmm.
- [Braxton] And you know,
they never came out the front.
- [K. Jones] Yeah, 'cause
we were at the front.
I didn't think she got shot,
it hit her because I was close,
so I was thinking like blood
would be on me or something,
but I didn't see nothin.
- [Braxton] Okay.
(objects fumbling)
You work, sweetie?
- [Kenn K] Nuh-uh.
Yeah, you really are,
you just turned 21.
- [K. Jones] Yeah.
(detective chuckles)
- [Braxton] And who do
you live with you now?
- [K. Jones] I live with my grandmother.
- [Braxton] And that's who live at 52 53rd Street?
- [K. Jones] No, my mom.
- [K. Jones] Well, I live, like-- I live with both, so.
Like, I would say.
- [Braxton] Okay. So they both live at that address?
- [K. Jones] No, my grandmama lives on 4824 B Street.
- [Braxton] 48-
- [K. Jones] 24.
- [Braxton] Mhm.
- [K. Jones] B Street.
- [Braxton] B, or-
- [K. Jones] As in ball.
- [K. Jones] Street Southeast.
- [Braxton] I know where that's at.
- [Braxton] She live on the house side or the apartment side?
- [K. Jones] The house.
- [Braxton] And what's your grandmother's name?
- [K. Jones] Diane.
- [Braxton] Mhm.
- [K. Jones] Jenkins.
- [Braxton] And you got a phone number for Grandma?
- [K. Jones] 2-0-2-
7-9-3-
9-1-9-4.
- [Braxton] So seeing how you said
everything was pretty much blank,
you said some things
you just can't remember,
like when she got
outside, stuff like that?
- [K. Jones] Mm hmm.
- [Braxton] But you know for sure
that's the same boy in the picture...
The video that you showed
me and stuff like that?
- [K. Jones] Yeah.
- [Braxton] Okay.
And he didn't say nothin else, after-
- [K. Jones] If he did, I can't
remember what he said.
- [Braxton] Well, after the gunshot,
what did your girlfriend Tamiyah say?
- [K. Jones] I didn't even see her no more,
I don't even remember.
I don't know how I got from
the door downstairs.
Like, I don't.
- [Braxton] Okay.
Now your cousin that's out there,
is that your blood cousin?
- [K. Jones] Yeah, by marriage.
- [Braxton] By marriage?
- [K. Jones] Mhm.
- [Braxton] You married?
- [K. Jones] No.
- [Braxton] Okay.
- [K. Jones] My mom.
Your mom, okay.
What's her name?
- [K. Jones] Deshawna.
- [Braxton] Deshawna? D-E or D-A?
- [K. Jones] I'm not sure.
- [Braxton] Okay, I'll get it from her when I talk to her.
All right, sweetie,
is there anything else
you can think about?
Do you remember what the boy was wearing
or anything like that?
- [K. Jones] It's in the video that I sent you.
- [Braxton] Okay.
So everything,
pretty much what he looked like
and everything like that,
that's the same boy you're sayin you saw?
- [K. Jones] Yes.
- [Braxton] Okay.
And you saw him two occasion,
and once on Thursday, Thursday.
- [Braxton] This past Thursday?
- [K. Jones] Yes.
- [Braxton] And once today.
I'll ask this. When y'all first got there
and when y'all saw him,
what was his demeanor like?
- [K. Jones] He was already pacin
with his hand on his hip.
But I don't know why,
if it's just three females,
it's not like it was guys with the...
If it was a guy or something,
I see if-
- [Braxton] Right, right, right.
- [K. Jones] I see the
reason of him doing that,
but it was literally just three girls.
- [Braxton] Well, you know,
some of these young people-
- [K. Jones] Well they're little and I'm like
a nice ass, I would say.
- [Braxton] Okay.
(detective chuckling)
Okay, if you say so!
I don't argue with people.
- [K. Jones] I'm sayin like,
body language and stuff, too.
Everything.
So if we would've been in our pockets
or I would've had my hand on the mig then,
I would see him trying to retaliate.
- [Braxton] Kendall,
I never saw Kendall,
what is she?
- She's like short, a
little shorter than me,
but she not built like me,
I used to box and stuff,
but she like a regular girl.
She's a shrimpy girl.
- [Braxton] Thin.
- [K. Jones] Medium.
- [Braxton] Medium, okay.
And your cousin? I haven't seen her.
- [K. Jones] She is small.
- [Braxton] Okay, like?
- [K. Jones] She's short and she boney.
- [Braxton] Okay, got you.
So you used to box?
- [K. Jones] Yeah, I did.
- [Braxton] Okay, I got you.
So you good with your hands, then?
- [K. Jones] Yeah, but I don't use my hands.
- [Braxton] I feel you,
there's nothing wrong with that.
Well, I'm sorry you had to go
through something like this.
- [K. Jones] Me too.
- [Braxton] We're working on all we can
trying to bring this to closure, okay?
So I'm gonna tell you what's gonna happen,
I'm gonna take you back out
here and sit you up front,
and now I gotta talk to your cousin,
ask her some questions.
And then after I finish,
what's gonna happen then,
I'm gonna talk to a couple
more detectives I work with,
and then we're gonna have
you taken back to your house.
Okay?
- [K. Jones] We have to go back to my house,
My car is there.
- [Braxton] How'd, y'all
get over there, by your car?
What kind of car you got?
- [K. Jones] A silver Honda.
Okay, what year?
- [K. Jones] 2000. The year I was born.
Okay.
So that's how y'all got over, by your car?
All three of ya?
And where'd you park your car at?
- [K. Jones] In front of her house.
- [Braxton] Right in
front of the building.
- [K. Jones] Like a little up.
- [Braxton] Okay.
- [K. Jones] It was a car in front.
- [Braxton] And Kendall
called, let her know, called-
- [K. Jones] Yeah, he said it was two here,
that's why I'm thinking,
like he got there moments
before we got there.
Or, you know what I'm sayin?
Because her demeanor changed.
At first it was cool
that when we got there,
it was like...
It was confusing me.
- [Braxton] So when you
talked to her on the phone,
she was cool, everything was fine.
- [K. Jones] Yeah, because Kenzo was like,
we come in to get the rest of our stuff.
She was "All right, bet."
be she was like, "Let me
know when y'all outside."
But we didn't think...
We didn't call like,
"Hey, we outside."
We just knocked on the door.
And she was like this,
but then the boy walk back,
and we put our foot right there.
I don't know if she's in danger,
'cause she always get in
domestic violence-like situation.
I don't know.
- [Braxton] But y'all
let her know we know
not here to 'cause any problems.
- [K. Jones] Yeah, I told
her like plenty of times,
we not here, we not on nothing.
If we was on somethin
I would've had...
'Cause I seen him Thursday, I was like,
"Bro, can you come until one
of my brothers come with me
or something.
And then I know her kids being there,
so like me, I'm a mom myself,
I'm not problematic.
- [Braxton] So you figured
with her kid being there,
nothing like this-
- [K. Jones] Yeah, I'm
thinking he was like this,
I'm seeing this little boy on the floor.
I'm like he not gonna
do nothing, but he did.
So it was just like,
you don't even respect her
kid like that, it just.
- [Braxton] So do you know her mother?
- [K. Jones] I don't personally know her,
but I ran into it with
her like a couple times.
- [Braxton] Okay.
And so you said the
only place you can think
she would go if she left,
would be her mom's house?
- [K. Jones] Yeah, but I'm not sure
if she would go there, though.
'Cause she got four kids,
so I'm trying to like...
I don't know 'cause...
I don't know.
- [Braxton] How old is your little one?
- [K. Jones] She's four.
- [Braxton] Oh,
okay. What's her name?
- [K. Jones] Karter. With a K.
(detective exhales)
How old was her child that was in there?
- [K. Jones] He's four, too.
- [Braxton] He's four, too?
- [K. Jones] Yeah.
- [Braxton] What's his name?
- [K. Jones] Zayden.
- [Braxton] Zayden?
- [K. Jones] Mhm.
That's bad, something like
that happen for a little boy.
- [K. Jones] But this not, it's like,
somethin happened a long
time ago, or something.
She was telling me,
but she didn't go into
detail and I don't know,
I don't know.
- [Braxton] Okay.
Is there anything else you can think of
that you think of would
shed some light on this
about what this might...
Other than y'all coming
over to get clothes,
you have no idea.
- [K. Jones] Honestly, that's what I'm sayin.
She must have told him,
I don't know what she told him about us
'cause me and her, we were
the closest outta everybody.
And we only got distance because,
the boy she used to deal with,
he came back in her life,
but this is not the same guy,
'cause I used to hang with him, as well,
so I know what he looks exactly.
I know his name and stuff,
but that's not the same guy.
- [Braxton] What was that guy's name?
- [K. Jones] His name was Bishop.
- [Braxton] Okay.
- [K. Jones] Yeah, but that's not him.
Cause he's a boney guy,
he's real tall, that's not him.
I know exactly what he looked like
'cause I used to hang with him.
But that's what I'm sayin,
I don't know what...
I don't know.
- [Braxton] And you
say she had been a victim
of domestic violence before?
- [K. Jones] Yeah.
- [Braxton] And you
don't know if this is,
other than what she had posted,
it seemed like this is a new relationship
she had been involved in.
- [K. Jones] Yeah, 'cause
I never seen this boy,
she never mentioned him or nothin.
- [Braxton] Okay.
When did y'all stop staying there?
- [K. Jones] I would say a little time
after her birthday.
- [Braxton] And when's that?
- [K. Jones] May, her birthday's May 16.
- [Braxton] So do
you know about how long
she'd been with this dude?
- [K. Jones] No.
- [Braxton] The picture
of your girlfriend
sent you the video,
what date is that on that video?
- [K. Jones] She sent it July 2nd.
- [Braxton] Okay.
So between May
and July 2nd,
had y'all been talking during that time?
- [K. Jones] Yeah, we were cool,
regularly talking.
But I wouldn't like hang with her no more.
- [Braxton] What made y'all stop hangin?
- [K. Jones] She started
dealing back with the guy
I just told you about,
the abusive boyfriend the first time.
And me and him got into it and stuff.
- [Braxton] That's the Bishop dude?
- [K. Jones] Yeah, we had
got into it and stuff,
but he never gave me...
He would hit her again
because he knew how
much we cared about it.
So her and him broke up, or whatever,
and after that she just
kept being distant.
So that's the last time.
- [Braxton] But you say,
you know this dude here is not the dude Bishop she was with.
- [K. Jones] That's not him at all.
- [Braxton] Okay.
But that's what made y'all stop
chilling together, 'cause-
- [K. Jones] She became,
no, not because of this,
she became distant after they broke up.
- [Braxton] After they broke up.
Wow, that's messed up.
- [K. Jones] But I'm thinkin, when that boy,
I'm trying to piece it together.
He said, "I just came home."
I was thinking maybe when he came home
they started dealing
back, so I don't know.
It's just hard, I don't know.
- [Braxton] So when that
dude say he just came home,
you figured somebody she may
have messed with in the past
or some dude she met.
- [K. Jones] Mm hmm.
- [Braxton] Okay.
About how old does that dude look?
- [K. Jones] At least 24 through 26,
he was in his early twenties.
- [Braxton] In his early twenties?
- [K. Jones] But looks can be deceiving
'cause kids nowadays look older now.
(detective chuckles)
- [Braxton] Some of them.
- [K. Jones] Yeah.
- [Braxton] Some of
'em look young still.
- [K. Jones] Like me.
- [K. Jones] Yeah, 'cause I really didn't think you were 21 at first.
I thought you were like, 16.
So, okay.
All right, well thank you
for being so straightforward,
let me know what's going on.
I'm gonna go out here,
I'm gonna take time to
talk to your cousin.
Okay, you okay?
- [K. Jones] Yeah.
- [Braxton] All right.
You think she gonna need them tissues?
- [K. Jones] Yeah,
she'll probably cry, too.
Thank you (indistinct).
(door opens)
(detective's comments indistinct)
(door closes)